EKAMPREET KAUR

+1(206) 602-9111 ¤ Redmond, WA

kaur.ekampreet@outlook.com x https://www.linkedin.com/in/ekampreetkaur/ x https://github.com/KaurEkampreet

OBJECTIVE

Seeking Technical Program Manager role to leverage my skills to build inclusive solution and continue to cultivate a culture of belonging in the workplace. Professional experience of 2.5+ years in planning, defining, implementing, and leading the development of key initiatives for software and services with guiding principle of Technical Program Management.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in Software Development, Green River College	Jan 2018 - Dec 2020
Software Development Deep Stack Certificate, Kal Academy	May 2020 - Sept 2020
Database Analyst Certificate, Bellevue College	Sept 2016 - Sept 2017

SKILLS

Technical Skills: C#, ASP.NET, Power BI, HTML, CSS, MS-SQL (IaaS, PaaS, On-Premises) Azure, Xamarin **Program Management:** Agile, Customer Relationship Management, Scrum, Strategic Planning, Roadmap Building **Tools and Design Pattern:** Visual Studio, GitHub, Postman, Docker, SSMS, Eclipse, MVC, Microservices

EXPERIENCE

Program Manager (Volunteer) | My Technology Geeks

Jan 2021 - July 2021

- Collaborated with engineering, product, and design teams to define fast-paced, but realistic schedules.
- Generated, prepared, and planned sprint ahead to reduce sprint planning time.
- Developed business objectives and track progress to ensure project milestones are on time, on budget and with the desired result

Software Engineer (Full-Time) | Microsoft

Sept 2017 - Feb 2019

- As an Interim Technical Program Manager responsible for design, implementing, defining, and documenting the compliant data platform which would adhere to the GDPR, Security and other industry standard data processing.
 - Defined the process of data ingestion, archival of data and access methods through Azure Active Directory and Service Principals.
 - Defining data contracts and Service Level Agreements for data usage and reporting purposes.
 - Responsible for communication and commitments for timely delivery to meet customer expectations.
- Implemented E2E Industry standard Failure Mode Effect Analysis as part of risk management for internal application.
 - Helped to identify telemetry, projects failure gaps which were addressed in sub sequentially sprints.
 - Created project documentation and strategic planning, collaborated with engineers to determine project timeline and milestones.
- Delivered end-to-end software engineering services consisting of
 - Application deployment, improving telemetry, Azure optimization (cost reduction, infrastructure management), feature designing, developing automating Live Site and Service Health Dashboards to enable high visibility of infrastructure and services.

Software Engineer (Intern) | Microsoft

March 2017 - Sept 2017

- Developed Service Health Dashboards for IT Authorize (Internal Application to Microsoft) to proactively monitor the health of services using Power BI, SQL, and Application Insights.
- Developed automated User Clean Up tool that connects to SQL database, compare user status with Microsoft Graph and Azure Active Directory, returns only non-active users to sync the status and remove non-active users from the system.

Dashboard Tracker:

• Design, build and maintain opportunity tracker tool leveraging PowerBI that provides and analytics to measure output and impact used by leadership team to make key strategic decisions regarding program strategy and operations.

Facility Management Scheduling Program:

- As a Scrum Developer. Worked on creating CRUD functionalities for a Facility Maintenance Scheduling Program for the Auburn School District.
- Enabled data integration and automate cleaning schedule, bringing efficiency to janitorial facility management.
- Seamlessly integrated the front-end with back-end services and migrated client's data using Json, Spring Boot, Hibernate, GitHub, and IntelliJ.

Eventbrite:

- Designed and implemented Microservices (C#, .NET) like Catalog service, Token services, Cart service, Order service and Integrated strip for Payment.
- Built the Restful Web API using C#, ASP.NET core framework, MVC Design pattern, Domain Driven design and performed CURD operations.
- Extended Restful APIs technology for designing Razor pages along with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Dockerized the application.